mentalhelp.net 2001-04-06

# Mental Help Net - Privacy Statement

**   Information Gathered: **  
  
Mental Help Net (MHN) gathers information from the people who use our site so that we can offer our users a better, more fulfilling experience. We gather this information in a manner that provides for protection of personal privacy, and with an eye towards maintaining the security of all gathered information. This document details how we go about collecting, maintaining and storing your information.   
  
**  General Information Gathering **  
  
**a) Web Server Logs**  
Like most sites, we keep a running record of what pages are requested on our site. Our web server logs contain information about what pages are most popular, and how many pages are viewed in a given time period. 

**b) Search Engines**  
We **do not** track search engine usage. No records are kept of any searches you might perform on MHN. 

**c) Community Database  
**We use Webboard software (O'reilly and Associates) for our community. This software mandates users create accounts which are stored in a database. Users need not supply any identifying information upon creating accounts, although they are free to do so if they wish. See notes below concerning the Professional Community for additional data gathering.   
  
**  Specific Site Resources Where Information Is Collected **  
  
**a) Community Registration**

Collection Point: on the [Community Registration page](http://forums.mentalhelp.net/forums/login.cgi?action=New&config=general)

Registration Information is maintained: On Site

We require that you complete a registration process before you can gain entry into our forums and chats (our community area). We require that you give us your name and a valid email address where you may be reached. You may provide additional optional information if you wish. 

We maintain a professional community that is closed to lay users. We ask that potential users of this system submit information concerning their professional backgrounds to aid MHN staff in determining eligibility for this professional resource. 

**b) Email Newsletter**

Collection Point: on home page at the bottom of the screen or at the NewsLetter Signup page

Registration Information is maintained: Off Site at Postmaster General

Persons desiring to receive our Twice Monthly Newsletter must first provide us with their Email address. Registration for the Newsletter is completely optional 

**c) Yellowpages Registration**

Collection Point: on the [ Yellowpages Signup page](http://mentalhelp.net/mhn/yellowpages/db.cgi?signup_form=1)

Registration Information is maintained: On Site

Clinicians who wish to sign up for our free clinician listings must register by completing a form listing information about their practice. Placing information into the Yellowpages database is completely optional 

**d) JobLink Database**

Collection Point: on the [ JobLink Signup page](http://mentalhelp.net/joblink/)

Registration Information is maintained: On Site

Users may submit job listings and resumes to our site. This service is completely optional.   
  
**  Use Of Cookies On MHN **  
  
**a) Automatic Logon to the Community Areas**  
Frequent visitors to our community area may optionally have our server 'remember' their user name and password by saving references to this information on to the users' computer in a "cookie" file (a text file that allows web sites to store and read information on your computer relevant to your web accounts). MHN does not place any _personally_ identifying information into this cookie file. Your Mental Help Net User ID automatically identifies your computer -- but not you -- to our servers when you visit our site. Unless you specifically tell us, Mental Help Net will never know who you are, even though we assign your computer a cookie. Cookie use is completely optional. 

**b) Third Party Cookies Embedded In Ad Banners**  
Advertising on MHN helps us to bring our services to you at absolutely no cost. The price of this free service is that companies placing ad banners on our site have the ability to assign your computer a cookie that uniquely identifies your computer. The ad cookies identify your computer and not your personal identity. The banner cookies are used by the ad companies to keep track of which ad banners you click on. The ad companies are interested in building up a profile of what you purchase so that they can send you ads that you are likely to be interested in when you visit in the future. MHN does not share any information with the ad companies that would allow them to link your personal identity to the cookie ID number they may have assigned you.   
  
**  Use Of The Information **  

MHN uses the information we gather from you for several purposes:  

a) We analyze what our customers like and don't like about Mental Help Net's current offerings so that we can design better services. 

b) MHN does not engage in profiling (e.g., matching your computer with your interests). However, our network ad server FlyCast may use profiling 

c) We develop summary -- not individual -- reports for our advertisers. An example of a summary report might be "200 people clicked on your advertisement "X" today." Advertisers use this information to track the effectiveness of their ad campaigns. We never tell our advertisers who it was that saw or clicked on their advertisements. 

d) The community registration information is used in several ways. First, registration serves as a means of allowing you to be uniquely identified, so that users can keep track of who said what. Second, you may optionally have our forum software place your email address into messages you send so that people can mail you personally in response. Third, we use the registration information to identify and communicate with persons who post inappropriate messages in the forums and chats. The registration also serves as a means of blocking known abusive users from entering the community. Fourth, we use information gathered by prospective applicants to our professional community to determine eligibility (to aid in our discrimination between lay persons and professional clinicians). 

e) Subscribers to our newsletter receive twice monthly email newsletters including information about new products and services from Mental Help Net. Mental Help Net uses the services of Postmaster General (A third party list-server company) to help with the mailing of our newsletter. Your email address is stored on the Postmaster General computer (and not on MHN's computer). Postmaster General's privacy policy protects the privacy and security of your email address. 

f) MHN clinicians can post yellowpages listings, resumes and jobs to our databases. This information is made available to the public for searching.   
  
**  Information Removal **  

a) We regularly remove outdated postings from our discussion forums. We will also remove any posting to our discussion forums or mailing list archives from any individual author if they let us know (contact the Webmaster). 

b) We regularly remove users and all of their identifying information from our computer systems when their accounts have become inactive (no usage for longer than 6 months) or their e-mail address expires.   
  
**  User Control Over The Information **  

In most cases, you have the ability to view and modify your information:

**a) Community Registration**  
You may view, modify, and/or control the use of most of your registration information. For instance, you can tell us if you don't want to be listed in service directories, such as user listings in our chat rooms. Access the form for controlling your forum experience by selecting "options" from the navigation bar at the top of the screen while you are viewing a message in the forums. You will need to be logged into the forums in order to access this feature. Click on "Profile" in our chat rooms to update your user information there. If you would like your account completely deleted, please drop us a note and we'll take care of it for you. 

**b) Newsletter**  
You can tell us if you don't want to receive communication from Mental Help Net such as our e-mail newsletter. You can remove yourself from the newsletter distribution list at any time by either following the directions included at the bottom of the newsletter, or by going to the bottom of our homepage, entering your email and pressing the remove button. 

**c) Yellowpages**  
You may edit your account provided you can supply the system with the username and password you were assigned when you created your listing. (Lost your password? Contact the Webmaster). 

**d) JobLink**  
Contact the Webmaster directly concerning deletion of materials from the JobLink Databases.   
  
**  Special Security Considerations **  

MHN employs uniform security measures (which are not here disclosed in order to protect the safety of your information) across all information collection points. We do not ask you for highly sensitive information (e.g., medical status, credit card numbers, etc.) , so there is little need for a special class of high security information collection procedures.   
  
**  Distribution Of The Information**  

_Mental Help Net will never willfully disclose individually identifiable information about its users to any third party without first receiving that individual's permission._

a) The individually identifiable information that you provide will be used for MHN purposes only. 

b) MHN does not share information with third parties except as identified below in "Appendix A: Third Party Partners" 

c) Where sharing does occur (e.g., optional storage of your email address on the Postmaster General server if you want to receive the newsletter), it is in the interest of making your experience of MHN a more pleasant and cohesive one. We do not form alliances with companies who will misuse or compromise the security of your information. 

d) Other companies which place advertising on our site may collect information about you when you view or click on their advertising or content. Mental Help Net does not control this ad-related collection of information. You should contact these advertisers or content providers directly if you have any questions about their use of this information (see information for FlyCast - our network ad server \- below in Appendix A: Third Party Partners). 

## Privacy Policy Appendices  
  
**  Appendix A: Third Party Partners**  

MHN has formed relationships with the following third party companies in order to bring you a more compelling web experience. We share some degree of information with these services (full details below). 

We do not and will not do business with Third Party Partners who do not guarantee the safety and security of your information. Our Third Party Partners have explicit privacy policies that guarantees the security and safety of your information. However, we do not bind Third Party Partners to meeting every standard of our own privacy policy. 

**FlyCast Network Ads**  
Privacy Policy: <http://www.flycast.com/about_us/about-privacy.html>

Mental Help Net works with the FlyCast Network to serve banner ads to our site. FlyCast ads may attempt to set cookies on your computer. These cookies may be used by FlyCast to construct an advertising profile of your likes and dislikes - so that you start to see more ads on things you are interested in purchasing. FlyCast reports that they will not attempt to connect your personal identity to this advertising profile. 

**Postmaster General**  
Privacy Policy: <http://www.postmastergeneral.com/privacy.html>

Postmaster General hosts the mailing list for our Newsletter. If you've signed up for the news letter, your email address is stored on their computer. You are always free to remove your email address from this list. 

**EXP**  
Privacy Policy: <http://www.exp.com/static_out/privacy_statement.htm>

MHN has an affiliate relationship with EXP.com, a website where people can get their questions (including relationship and therapy questions) answered by 'experts'. When you visit EXP from MHN, we pass our name on to them so that they know you are visiting from our site. EXP is a for profit company that charges a fee for its services. MHN gets a percentage of all completed transactions we refer to them. 

**cPulse**  
Privacy Policy: <http://mentalhelp.net/about/privacy_cpulse_faq.htm>

MHN works with cPulse to survey our readership on the quality of MHN's resources. MHN uses this information to better learn what our readership wants from our site, so that we can set priorities for how to make our site better. The cPulse survey pops up at random and is completely optional; there is no need to fill it out if you don't want to. The information gathered becomes the 

_property_

of cPulse, who then releases it back to MHN. 

**Zoomerang:**  
Privacy Policy: <http://www.zoomerang.com/privacy/index.html>

On occasion, MHN uses the Zoomerang web survey tool to conduct surveys of our readership. Participation in these surveys is completely optional. The collected data is stored on the Zoomerang web servers, but is released back to MHN for analysis.
